<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on glumia's blog</title><link>https://glumia.github.io/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on glumia's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glumia.github.io/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Clojure, Python, C: three programming languages, one algorithm</title><link>https://glumia.github.io/blog/clojure-python-c-three-programming-languages-one-algorithm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glumia.github.io/blog/clojure-python-c-three-programming-languages-one-algorithm/</guid><description>Too lazy to write something long and well thought now ¯\_(ツ)_/¯
Just a bit disappointed by how bad Clojure&amp;rsquo;s performance are (but hey, immutability is not free!) and by how damn difficult it is to improve them.
Update 23/06/20 I found out that the timing of the C version goes down to ~2ms if I just declare the variables as int and not unsigned int. That&amp;rsquo;s amazing!
Update 09/01/21 Half I year later I finally know why the version with signed integers actually takes less than the version with unsigned ints.</description></item><item><title>The Levenshtein Distance</title><link>https://glumia.github.io/blog/the-levenshtein-distance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glumia.github.io/blog/the-levenshtein-distance/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating how everything you can think of in computer science 9 times out of 10 was already thought and probably studied by someone else. Today I was thinking about a way to suggest corrections for addresses inserted by our customers when I started to imagine an algorithm that used the mathematical notion of &amp;lsquo;distance&amp;rsquo; (check &amp;lsquo;Metric (mathematics)&amp;rsquo; on Wikipedia 1 ) to give them some suggestions based on a set of valid addresses present on our DB.</description></item><item><title>GOG Store - Overkill search</title><link>https://glumia.github.io/blog/gog-store-overkill-search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glumia.github.io/blog/gog-store-overkill-search/</guid><description>I had 1.30 euro remaining on my GOG wallet and I had to use them before Sept. 19 or they would expire. I started to look for a game but store&amp;rsquo;s search engine didn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to filter them for a price in a custom range. I could only search for games whose price was less than 5 euros, and this still yield to 530 results. Too many to check them one by one.</description></item></channel></rss>